Welcome to our training on toys and compliance.
At Amazon, safety is our top priority.
As a seller in the Amazon store, it's your responsibility to know and comply with all laws and regulations
and Amazon policies that apply to each of your products, including specific requirements based on
their age grading.
If you wish to sell children's toys in the United States, we'll ask you to provide certain documentation
to confirm your products meet applicable children's toy safety standards.
A toy is any item designed for play.
When selling toys in the US, one of the requirements you must comply with is ASTM F963-17, which
is the standard consumer safety specification for toy safety.
We'll refer to this as the toy safety standard.
This standard details the test methods for toys intended for use by children ages 12 years and under.
As the Consumer Product Safety Commission, or CPSC, explains on its website, the toy safety standard
provides for many different types and classes of toys.
Different sections of the toy safety standard apply to different toys.
It's your responsibility to know which section applies to the toys you wish to list in the Amazon
store.
All children's toys you list in the US Amazon store must also adhere to the Consumer Product Safety
Improvement Act, or CPSIA.
We'll discuss this requirement later on.
Let's look at a few examples regarding the toy safety standard.
John sells a toy that doesn't produce any sound, so the section of the toy safety standard that
limits how loud a sound the toy makes won't apply to his toy.
Mateo sells a toy that contains small parts and is intended for children aged three to six.
One requirement for the toy is that it must be labeled to inform the buyer that it isn't for use
by children under three years old because it's a choking hazard.
Lee sells a plastic baseball bat and ball set, considered to be a toy, and must comply with the
toy safety standard.
She also sells an adult aluminum baseball bat that isn't a toy but is considered a sports good.
Sports goods that aren't toys such as the adult aluminum bat won't need to comply with the toy safety
standard.
If you're unsure if the toy safety standard applies to your product or which sections are applicable
for your toy, you may want to consult a CPSC accepted testing lab.
As mentioned earlier, all children's toys you list in the US Amazon store must also adhere to the
CPSIA.
In accordance with this regulation, we'll ask you to submit a children's product certificate or
CPC from the manufacturer or importer of your toy, as well as test reports from a CPSC accepted
third-party testing lab accredited to test to the ASTM F963-17 toy safety Standard.
Compliance documentation and information must verify that your products meet the requirements applicable
to your toy.
It must also confirm your product was tested to the ASTM F963-17 toy safety standard and any other
applicable CPSIA standards, such as the limit on the amount of lead in children's products.
The test reports must contain images of the tested products, including the packaging, age grading,
warning labels and tracking label.
The images of the tracking label must clearly show the names of the manufacturer or distributor,
the location and date of manufacture,
detailed information on the manufacturing process, such as a batch or run number or other identifying
characteristics, and any other information that describes the toy's source.
It's important to note that the information in the test reports and on all packaging, labels and
images must match the information on your product's detail page.
If you're registered with the CPSC as a small batch manufacturer or SBM, ensure that your SBM number
is displayed on the CPC.
For more information, visit CPSC's webpage on SBM compliance by searching for CPSC.
gov followed by SBM.
Remember to also visit the CPSC website at CPSC.
gov for a list of their accepted labs.
Some labs provide special Amazon rates for testing.
To find more information about these providers, visit the Service Provider Network page in Seller
Central.
The CPSC's website is a useful resource when listing children's toys in the Amazon store.
Here you can find guidance for businesses on what is considered a toy, age determination guidelines
for toys and other children's products,
a list of accepted testing labs, tracking label information, small business manufacturer information
and other information about children's toy requirements.
Information contained in this module doesn't constitute legal advice and is for general informational
purposes only.
Remember that you can find more information on determining if your product is a toy as well as a
list of approved labs by visiting the CPSC website at CPSC.
gov.
To learn more about listing toys in the Amazon store, search for "selling children's toys in the
U.
S.
in Seller Central."
This concludes our training on toys and compliance.
Thank you and happy selling in the Amazon store!